# 火焰醉龙虾
Crayfish in flame
# 起火儿 三叔一等一天啦
Here we go. San Shu has been waiting whole day for this.
# 看来要炸啊
Looks like he is going to deep fry it
# 烧热点儿 赶紧窜一下得了
Get the oil hot and fry it quickly
# 把这水篦干了
Let's drain it first.
# 二哥倒
Pour it in!
# 它往这边喷啊
The steam is coming out this way
# 炸一下 不脆二哥搁点醋去腥
Deep-frying removes the fishy smell as well as using vinegar
# 也是为了让肉有弹性 紧实
It also makes it more firm
# 它那个不好的味道都去掉了
Indeed, it removes all the unwanted smells
# 而且颜色还挺漂亮的
It also gives a nice color
# 崩开 崩开的意思是什么啊 易于进味儿
The frying makes the crayfish more "open" to absorb the flavors.
# 我就不炸
I wouldn't fry it though.
# 给我拿点儿海米来
Can you pass the dried shrimps to me?
# 海米没给你泡啊 不用泡
- We didn't soak it in advance.
- That's alright.
# 看着啊 这海米跟虾要碰撞 小火慢炒啊
We must fry the dried shrimps and the crayfish slowly with low heat.
# 有点味儿就行 能提鲜啊 葱姜
Get the flavors out (Spring onion and ginger in)
# 料酒呢
Where is the cooking wine?
# 花雕酒啊
"Huadiao" rice wine.
# 这下料真狠啊
That's quite a lot of seasoning.
# 着什么啊 醪糟
What is that? Laozao (rice wine distiller grains)
# 醪糟龙虾 这不南方菜吗
Crayfish with Laozao, that's a southern dish.
# 不知道的以为是米饭炒小龙虾呢
It's almost like fried rice with crayfish.
# 看见没有啊
See?
# 南方管他叫醉龙虾
They call this the "drunken" crayfish in the south.
# 醉 拿酒 拿什么酒呢 拿米酒
As it was cooked with rice wine.
# 应该是在十一到十二度吧 咱还有十七度的
The rice wine is at about 11-12%, sometimes up to 17%
# 还真好看
Looks good.
# 好 盐 嚯 糖够多了
Ok now, sugar and salt. (That's a lot of sugar)
# 火焰小龙虾啊
Crayfish in flame
# 四弟赶紧拍 要不然到时候就没了啊
Sidi, film it quickly before the flame goes out.
# 这是火焰小龙虾 要的就是这一下
Here we have it, the crayfish in flame. We waited so long for this moment.
# 一直大火在催 不能小火炖 把这个汁收了
We have to keep reducing the sauce on high heat.
# 差不多 差不多
Almost done
# 大爷 拿个勺您先来尝尝
Da Ye, grab a spoon and have a taste first.
# 好 你看这汁儿就够甜的
The sauce looks sweet.
# 嘿 酒香味浓 虾味鲜香
Nice flavor from the rice wine and the crayfish
# 甜度够么 甜度可以
Is it sweet enough? Yes
# 我尝尝我尝尝 等着等着
Let me have a taste. Wait wait it's coming.
# 实在是高
Really nice.
# 现在拿筷子开始把葱姜捡出来了
Let's pick the spring onion and ginger out.
# 怎么样味道
How was the taste?
# 一句话 簋街又添了道新菜
What can I say, a new signature dish on Guijie
(Famous food location in Beijing)
# 好了
It's done!
# 动作娴熟 敏捷
That was a quick and smooth move.
# 好 我们马上灭火 关火啦
OK, turn off the heat.
# 诶 亮不亮
Is that a nice bright color?(nice)
# 酒香虾鲜味儿足
Fragrant rice wine combined with nice flavor of the crayfish
# 色泽呢 鲜红 明亮
Color? Nice bright red.
# 三叔的火焰醉龙虾 奇招之下 必有惊喜
Crayfish in Flame by San Shu
An amazing recipe with unique techniques
# import ending.sbv 0:03:11.960